Suhas Pindiproli

San Diego, CA 92115

619-317-7196 | suhas.pindiproli@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/suhas-pindiproli/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative Full stack Developer with 4+ years of experience in designing and developing responsive websites that are optimized for mobile utilizing React.js, Typescript, Redux, CSS and SASS. I also possess experience in developing backend and deploying applications across multiple platforms, utilizing a variety of programming languages and frameworks such as Spring Boot, Django, Express.js and collaborated with cross functional team to integrate the RESTful API's and optimizing applications for performance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SellYourCar INC, CA | Full-stack Engineer

12/2023 - current

- Created reusable code libraries, reducing development time for future projects by 25% and improving the efficiency of the development team.
- Addressed server-frontend communication by connecting REST APIs from C# to React.js and reduced page loads by 15% by utilizing lighthouse for metrics.
- Delivered mobile first website utilizing Reactstrap and Material-UI (MUI), streamlining UI development for visually appealing and responsive interfaces.

ChangingThePresent Org, CA | Full-stack Engineer Volunteer

07/2023 - 12/2023

- Modified Database schema to utilize the business model and implemented relationship in MySQL.
- Designed RESTful APIs to provide the data from the MySQL in JSON format by utilizing PHP.
- Achieved sleek frontend on WordPress Admin, by connecting MySQL on WordPress Admin to utilize the data from the backend using PHP to provide the data on to the frontend.

NanoCellect Biomedical INC, CA | Software Development Engineer Intern

07/2022 - 12/2022

- Optimized latency in PostgreSQL by 10% using concept of de-normalization that provided faster response to the Complex Join queries.
- Devised Labelling System that brought down the manual efforts of labelling the product by 20% using React.js and Django
- Executed optimization of page loads by implementing code minification and tree shaking on Webpack, yielding improved site performance.
- Developed web services and APIs that enabled seamless communication between front-end and back-end components, enhancing application functionality.

Zensar Technologies, India | Software Engineer

10/2018 - 05/2021

- Refactored legacy code base from Java 1.7 to microservices architecture, resulting in improved scalability and reduced downtime utilizing Spring Boot framework.
- Designed frontend to ensure responsive UI that there by ensuring reduction in debounce rate utilizing React.js and third-party library.
- Implemented automated build and deployment processes using Cloud bee Jenkins and Nexus Repository, reducing deployment times by 60% and minimizing production issues by 20%.
- Executed backend service integration with integrate with front-end technologies such as jQuery and AJAX to, resulting in real-time data-driven updates to the website and an improved user experience.

PROJECTS

University Course Registration Portal

- Implemented robust data fetching functionality using the Axios library to retrieve and manage data from external APIs, resulting in a 20% improvement in data retrieval speed.
- Secured user authentication tokens by leveraging the Local Storage API of JavaScript, reducing token-related security incidents by 30%.

Inventory Management System

- Designed and implemented a comprehensive inventory management system utilizing Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, React.js, MongoDB Atlas, and Bootstrap, resulting in a 40% increase in operational efficiency.
- Engineered a responsive and user-friendly user interface (UI) using React.js and the Bootstrap framework, leading to a 25% improvement in user satisfaction.
- Contributed to the creation of an efficient and scalable solution, reducing inventory errors by 15% and facilitating a 30% improvement in overall inventory management processes.

SKILLS

- Programming languages: Java | JavaScript | Python | Typescript
- Databases: PostgreSQL | MySQL | SQL | MongoDB
- Framework: Spring | React.js | Maven | Gradle | Junit | Mockito | Django
- Tools: AWS | Jira | POSTMAN | Webpack | Docker | Git | Storybook | Gulp | Webpack

CERTIFICATIONS

- Spring Framework in Depth
- Java
- React.js Essential Training

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science, Graduation Year 2023 San Diego State University, GPA 3.63, CA

Bachelors in Computer Engineering, Graduation 2018 Savitribai Phule Pune University, GPA 3.15, India